( INSECTS CHIRPING )
( LOON CALLS )
( CHIRPING CONTINUES )
( CROW CAWS IN DISTANCE )
Subtitles by explosiveskull Sync by GoldenBeard
( WIND CHIMES TINKLING )
( CROWS CAWING )
PET SEMATARY
( OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING )
( SOFT , OVERLAPPING WHISPERS )
( FIRE CRACKLING )
( SERENE INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING )
So many trees .
It 's beautiful , right ?
Well , it 's definitely not Boston .
- No , it 's not . - ( TOY CLATTERING )
ELLIE : Mom , make him stop . It 's not fair to Church .
- I 'm pretty sure Church is okay . - ( PURRING )
It 's not actually Church that I 'm worried about .
We 've still got another eight hours to go .
What ?
( LAUGHING )
Not funny , Dad .
That is so funny .
- I got you good . - ( RACHEL CHUCKLES )
- Gage , did you find that funny ? - RACHEL : I thought it was funny .
( ENGINE SHUTS OFF )
What do you think ?
- Wow . - " Wow " ? That 's it ?
It 's pretty incredible , don 't you think ?
I even got them to throw in a whole forest
as a new backyard .
This whole place is ours ?
This whole place is the new domain
of Ellie-phant the Great and Terrible .
I 'll tell you what .
Do you want to be the first inside ?
( WHISPERS ) Go , go , go .
RACHEL : The movers were here all morning ,
so everything should be inside .
Good .
- ( TRUCK ROARING ) - ( HORN BLARING )
Son of a bitch . You okay ?
Yeah , it just startled me a little bit .
LOUIS : You okay , Gage ?
- Big truck , huh ? - RACHEL : Who 's a brave boy ?
LOUIS : That was a big truck , wasn 't it ?
Okay . You ready , little man ?
- Here we go . Come on . - BOTH : One , two , three !
Home .
- ( RACHEL CHUCKLES ) - Hmm .
Well , he adapted quickly .
What about you ? You ready for the country life , Doc ?
- Well , let 's find out . Come on . ( GRUNTS ) - ( LAUGHING )
Mrs. Creed .
( RACHEL LAUGHS GLEEFULLY )
Wait , the cat 's in the car !
RACHEL : ( WHISPERING ) This all happened pretty fast . You gonna miss it ?
I don 't think anyone really misses the graveyard shift in the ER .
I don 't think that really answered my question .
- Hmm . - Hmm .
- Hey . - Hmm ?
You needed this .
We needed this .
I get to spend some more time around the house
- with the kids . - And your stay-at-home wifey .
- Ooh , I didn 't even think about that . - Yeah ?
- I may have to rethink that . - Oh , you will ?
- You stop that . Don 't you do that . - ( LAUGHING )
- Yeah ... - ( LAUGHING )
( INDISTINCT CHATTER )
Good morning , Marcella .
Ready for the storm ?
We have someone already ?
Bloody nose . Room 4 .
Sounds serious .
( FAINT DRUMBEATS IN DISTANCE )
Do you hear that ?
( DRUMBEATS GROW LOUDER )
( DRUMBEATS CONTINUE )
What are they doing ?
RACHEL : Looks like some sort of procession .
( DRUMBEATS CONTINUE )
What 's a procession ?
It 's like a parade , but not for fun .
Hey , let 's go back inside and watch a show .
I 'm tired of unpacking boxes .
- ( CARTOON PLAYING ON TV ) - ( RACHEL SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY )
RACHEL : ( ON PHONE ) Sooner than that .
I mean , Ellie 's birthday is coming up in a few months .
( CHATTER CONTINUES ON TV )
( CROW CAWING )
Well , I don 't know why you 're worried , Mom . No , everything 's fine .
The kids are really happy .
Yeah .
No , it 's nice to slow down a little bit ,
- you know ? - ( PAPER FLAPS )
Hey , Mom , can I , uh ... Can I talk to you later ?
Okay , love you . Bye .
Hey , Ellie , are you hungry ?
( WOOD CREAKING )
- Hey . You get down from there ! - ( GASPS )
- ( GASPS ) - ( BEES BUZZING )
( TWIG SNAPS )
( SIGHS )
The trick is ...
To get the stinger out real quick .
- ( WINCES ) - Oh , she 's a big ' un .
No prize winner ...
But she 'll do for a ribbon .
There you go .
Yeah .
Should be starting to quiet down now .
You 're the doctor 's little girl .
Eleanor Creed . But you can call me Ellie .
I 'm Judson Crandall .
You can call me Jud .
All right . Up you get .
- What is this place ? - Pet cemetery .
- Didn 't you read the sign ? - Yeah . They spelled it wrong .
These are all people 's pets ?
JUD : Well , the whole town 's been using this place for generations .
I saw those kids .
They were all wearing those masks .
Yeah .
A lot of folks make a kind of ritual out of it .
See this one over here ? I carved this myself .
That 's my dog , Biffer .
And it 's true . He was a hell of a sniffer .
RACHEL : Ellie ?
You know better than to wander off by yourself . Come here .
Mommy , this is Jud , our neighbor .
I got stung by a bee .
He pulled the stinger out . It was a big ' un .
Hmm . Nice to meet you , ma 'am .
Nice to meet you , too . I 'm Rachel , Ellie 's mom .
You know , these woods ...
It 's not really all that safe to go roaming around in ' em .
People can get lost up here .
Thank you , Jud . Um , we should get back , okay ?
Honey , you can 't wander off like that .
I don 't know where you are . I can 't do anything ...
Just wash the mud off and rub some baking soda on that sting .
( FAINT WHISPERING ) Jud ...
Come back ...
- ELLIE : Dad ? - LOUIS : Yeah ?
Why don 't pets live as long as people ?
Well ...
Do you remember that talk we had about metabolism ?
- The clock in your body ? - Yes .
Humans have a slow metabolism ,
a slow clock , so we live longer .
Whereas cats and dogs ...
Well , they have a fast metabolism .
Which means , when it runs out ...
They die and go to the pet cemetery .
RACHEL : Yeah . ( CLEARS THROAT )
Ellie discovered a charming little landmark
in the woods today , right in our backyard .
Okay . Well , that doesn 't have to be such a bad thing , does it ? Hmm ?
A place to bury our pets and remember them .
It might seem scary , but it 's not . It 's perfectly natural .
Just like dying is natural . Hmm ?
We all die and eventually , one way or another ,
we all go back into the ground .
What Daddy 's trying to say
is that even though the pet 's body goes in the ground ,
its soul keeps living and goes to heaven .
Just like Nana Creed .
Remember how I told you she 's looking down on you ?
Well , we don 't actually know
that it works exactly like that .
What Mommy and Daddy are trying to say
is that you don 't have to worry about this , sweetheart , okay ?
Church and Mommy and me , we 're gonna be around a long , long time .
And Gage ?
Of course , sweetie . Gage is just a kid .
But what about your sister , Mommy ?
Wasn 't she just a kid when she died ?
( FLOORBOARDS CREAKING )
( DOOR CREAKING )
( GIRL WHIMPERING FAINTLY )
( GIRL GROANING )
( RASPY VOICE ) Rachel ...
LOUIS : Rachel .
You okay ?
What was that in there ?
Funny , I wanted to ask you the same thing .
Rachel , Ellie 's almost nine years old .
We should be able to talk to her about this .
Ellie 's a child .
And death for her is scary .
Please , Rachel , doesn 't mean we should shield her from it .
And you think that 's what I 'm doing ?
I think that all this talk about the afterlife ,
about people looking down on her ,
I think ... Yeah , I think it 's delaying
getting to the heart of the matter , yes .
So , you ... You really don 't think there 's anything
after we die ? No heaven , no nothing ?
No .
Right . We 're gonna take a swab and run a test for strep .
It could be allergies ,
but we just want to be sure .
Marcella , please tell me it 's almost lunch .
If I have to look at another pair of swollen tonsils ,
- I swear to God ... - Judy went out for sandwiches .
( CHILDREN CLAMORING )
( PANTING ) His head !
MARCELLA : Victor , uh , Pascow .
It 's Victor Pascow . He 's a student here .
GIRL : He was skating and the car just came out of nowhere !
- He got dragged . - Call Life Flight to Bangor .
No time for an ambulance .
We need to get his blood type . We 'll need a lot of units .
We have to stabilize him before we can transfer .
NURSE 1 : He have a medical bracelet on ?
NURSE 2 : I didn 't see anything , no .
LOUIS : I 'm not gonna let you die , Victor . Shit .
Type O-positive . Pulling four units .
Great . Lie back , okay ? Just lie back . Lie back .
Let 's hurry up with those units , okay ?
Kelly , we 're gonna need to fit him with a cervical collar
to get him lifted .
His brain . I can see it .
Kelly . Kelly , go !
Victor , please .
Where are we with those units ? He 's losing a lot of blood !
( GASPING )
No . No , no , no , Victor . No . You stay with me , Victor .
You stay with me . I 'm right here , Victor . Stay right here ...
- ( WHIMPERS , GROANS ) - ( BONES CRACKING )
Come ... Come back to me , Victor .
Come on . Come back to me .
Come back . Come back .
( GRUNTS )
( SOFTLY ) God damn it .
( GLOVES SNAP )
( SIGHS )
( LIGHTS BUZZING )
( GROANS )
VICTOR : Louis .
The barrier is not meant to be broken .
- MARCELLA : Louis ? - ( GASPS )
( LOUIS BREATHING HEAVILY )
Uh , he 's gone .
( SIGHS )
( CAR ENGINE IDLING )
( BLOOD DRIPPING )
( TRUCK HORN BLARING )
( EXHALES )
( INHALES )
( SIGHS )
RACHEL : Hey .
What happened ?
This poor kid got hit by a car today
right on the campus .
He , uh , couldn 't have been more than 20 years old .
His name was Victor Pascow .
I sure wasn 't expecting to see any of that up here .
Why don 't you come inside ?
I 'll make you some dinner . You can take a shower . Okay ?
I 'm sorry .
He , uh , knew my name .
What ?
He ...
Nothing . Doesn 't matter .
Jud ? It 's Ellie . I made cookies .
Are you home ?
( DOOR CREAKING , CLOSES )
You in the habit of going through
- other people 's things ? - ( CLOSES DRAWER )
Sorry .
Is that your wife ?
Yeah . Her name was Norma .
She 's pretty .
What happened to her ?
Got sick . Passed away .
Well , maybe she 's still out there .
You know , watching from heaven ?
You think so , Ellie ?
Hey , want to come meet my cat ?
- His name is Church . - Church ?
That 's short for Winston Churchill .
He 's a guy who lived a long time ago .
Oh , I know who Winston Churchill is .
Wow . You must be really old .
- ( GIGGLES ) - ( CHUCKLES ) I 'm afraid so .
( DANCE OF THE SUGAR PLUM FAIRY PLAYING )
( CHUCKLING )
- LOUIS : Oh-ho ! - Very nice !
Very good .
- ( LAUGHTER ) - Nice job . Bravo , sweetheart .
- Can you clap ? Clap , clap . - Well done , honey .
Thanks , folks , for having me over .
It 's been a long time since I 've had any good home cooking .
How long have you lived here ?
What , in Ludlow , or in that house ?
- Either . - All my life .
To both questions .
( MEOWING )
- Whoa , big fella ! - Church !
- He likes you . - Well , I like him .
Church good kitty .
- Hey ! - Yes .
- Church good , good kitty . - He is .
- Yeah . - I was curious , Jud ...
Um , the realtor said the house came
with over 50 acres of woods .
That pet cemetery , do we own that , too ?
Well , that 's part of your property .
How far back is the property line ?
Well , it 's further than you 'd ever care to go .
( WIND CHIMES TINKLING )
( FAINT WHISPERING ) Louis .
( FAINT , OVERLAPPING WHISPERING )
- ( WHISPERS STOP ) - ( WIND CHIMES STOP )
( WOOD CREAKING )
( INDISTINCT WHISPERS RESUME )
( WIND CHIMES TINKLING )
VICTOR : Come on , Doc .
- ( LOUD THUMP ) - ( WOOD CREAKING )
( INDISTINCT WHISPERING CONTINUES )
( LOON CALLING )
VICTOR : You tried to help me .
Now let me help you .
This is the place where the dead rest .
Do not go on to the place
where the dead walk .
Stop ! The ground is sour !
- ( ROARING ) - ( GASPS )
Wake up , Dada !
( CHUCKLING ) Oh , hey , buddy .
Come here , come here , come here .
Come to Daddy .
( CHUCKLES )
- I love you , Daddy . - Hmm ?
Oh , man , thank you .
Time for Daddy to get up .
Hi .
- Good morning , sleepyhead . - Hey .
Did you wake up Dada ? Huh ?
- Did you wake up Dada , huh ? - What time is it ?
It 's late . You slept in .
( PEOPLE CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY )
( CHILDREN LAUGHING , CHATTERING )
- Hey , guys ! - CHILDREN : Hi , Ellie .
- What have you guys got ? - ( LOUIS CHUCKLING )
I 've got some candy corns , lollipops ...
They also have really big gummy bears .
Okay , which one is the sheet and which one is the gho ... Oh !
- You look like a ghost , don 't you , huh ? - ( BOTH GIGGLING )
You 've been busy already .
- You guys look great . - BOTH : Thank you .
GIRL : We have to go to the Pattersons ,
- ' cause they have the biggest candy ... - El , uh ...
- Take your broom , honey ? - Yeah .
Talk among yourselves .
- I 'll be back , okay ? - ELLIE : Okay .
What are you doing , Jud ? You scaring the kids ?
There 's something you need to see .
( CHILDREN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY )
All right .
Oh , no . Church .
One of those damn Orinco trucks .
- ELLIE : Dad ! - Oh , shit .
- Dad ! - Uh , we can 't let Ellie see this .
Come on , we got to go trick-or-treating
- with Zoe and Tyler . - Yeah , honey .
I 'm just gonna say a quick hello to Jud .
- Okay ? - I 'll put a spell on you .
You already have , sweetheart .
You go wait in the car , honey . I 'll be right there .
You , uh ... You go with the kids .
Come back later , we 'll take care of this .
( SIGHS )
Okay .
And , Louis ...
We should do this tonight .
Sure , yeah .
You 're sure ? ( SNIFFLES )
Yeah , I 'm sure .
I mean , he was all twisted .
( INHALES SHAKILY )
Which brings me
to the fact that we have to tell Ellie .
- No , can we just tell her ... - Rachel . No , we need ...
Can we just tell her that he ran away , please ?
You know , honey , I get it , okay ?
I get it 's difficult for you to talk about death
after what you went through with your sister ,
but I think it 's time you finally opened up .
I 'm just ...
No , I 'm just upset about Church .
Rachel , talk to me . We both know this is about Zelda .
ELLIE : Ever since moving here , I can 't stop thinking about her .
She hated me
because my spine wasn 't twisted like hers .
She promised me that one day I 'd end up just like her .
I 'd never get out of bed again .
My parents left me alone with her .
I was supposed to bring her dinner .
And so I used the dumbwaiter , and I knew I wasn 't supposed to
because it didn 't work all the time .
( DUMBWAITER WHIRRING )
- ( MUFFLED THUMPING ) - ( SCRAPING )
- ( THUMPING CONTINUES ) - ( SCRAPING CONTINUES )
( ZELDA GROANS )
- ( ZELDA SCREAMS ) - ( CRASHES )
( GASPS )
- ( METAL CREAKING ) - ( ZELDA BREATHING SHAKILY )
( THUMPING ON DOOR )
( GASPS )
( METAL CLANGS )
( SCREAMING )
She died in there because of me .
I watched them wheel her body out ,
but I swear she was still in the walls .
- ( WALLS BUMPING ) - ( WOOD CREAKING )
And at night , I could hear her moving ,
calling out my name .
ZELDA : ( WHISPERING ) Rachel .
I didn 't know who to call .
But if I had just gone up to the room and given her her food ...
Your parents should never have left you alone with her . Never .
That makes me a monster .
No , no , no , no , no , no ,
that does not make you a monster .
Come on . Hey .
That does not make you a monster . Okay ?
Mmm ?
Tell you what .
Jud and I are gonna take care of Church tonight . All right ? We 'll ...
We 'll just tell Ellie that he ran away .
- Okay ? Yeah ? - Okay .
Just anything but dead .
JUD : I got a spot for you .
What is it ?
Nothing . Let 's get this over with , huh ?
It 's cold .
( GRUNTING )
WOMAN : ( WHISPERING ) Jud ...
( LOUD BUZZING )
Jud ...
- ( DIRT CRUNCHES ) - ( SHOVEL SCRAPING )
Ellie really loved that cat , didn 't she ?
More than anything .
And you love Ellie .
( SIGHS )
Well , of course .
So , follow me .
What ?
- I know all the spots to step . - Jud , wait .
What 's the matter with right here ?
For Chrissakes .
( WOOD TAPPING )
( MUTTERING ) Oh , what the hell am I doing ?
( LOUIS GRUNTS )
Jud , come on , wait up .
What the hell is this place ?
- ( SOFT , OVERLAPPING WHISPERS ) - ( LOUIS PANTING )
- ( WINGS FLAPPING ) - ( BIRD CAWING )
( BRANCH SNAPS )
LOUIS : Come a long way to bury a cat .
( SNAPPING )
( THUNDER RUMBLING )
( SIGHS )
( BRANCHES RUSTLING )
- ( CREATURE WAILING ) - ( LOON CALLING )
What was that ?
It 's just a loon .
Come on .
( GRUNTING )
( LOUIS PANTING )
LOUIS : What is this place ?
- You feel that ? - Yeah .
Bury your animal .
I 'd help you , but you have to do it yourself .
And use some of these rocks to make a cairn .
- Kind of like the other ones . - Okay .
( THUNDER RUMBLING )
What exactly are we doing here tonight , Jud ?
We 're burying your daughter 's cat .
And that 's all ?
That and nothing but .
( THUNDER RUMBLES )
You did good , Louis .
I knew you would .
What time is it ?
It 's late .
Did you and Jud take care of everything ?
( SIGHS ) Yeah , it 's done .
Thank you .
ELLIE : What is it ?
It 's Church , honey .
Yeah .
Daddy and Jud went out last night to look for Church , and ...
Well , we looked all around and we ...
Well , sweetheart , we couldn 't find him .
And so we think ...
We think Church ran away , sweetheart .
- Yeah . - He didn 't run away .
RACHEL : Well ...
He was outside my window last night .
Honey , maybe you had a dream that you saw him .
( MUFFLED ) It 's okay to be confused about all this ...
You just have to accept that he might not come home .
( CLEARLY ) I 'm sorry , sweetie .
He came back last night .
Look .
He 's right there .
( RAGGED PURRING )
- ( HISSES ) - ( EXCLAIMS )
( LOW GROWLING )
I thought you said he was dead .
He was .
He , uh ...
He must 've been unconscious , in shock or something .
Good thing you 're not a fucking vet .
( LOW GROWLING )
Jud .
We , uh ...
We need to have a little talk .
Ellie 's cat is walking around over there like nothing happened .
Well , I 'll be damned .
What the fuck does that mean ?
Well , isn 't that what you wanted ?
Save your daughter from the truth ?
I mean , come on . You saw as well as I did .
- That cat was dead , Jud . - I never said he wasn 't .
- Well , then how do you explain it ? - I don 't .
( AXE CLATTERS )
Nobody can .
You 're gonna have to do better than that , Jud .
There are places in this world
that are older than either of us .
Places that a rational doctor brain like yours
will never understand .
Nobody knows what that place is ,
what happens in that stony ground .
But the soil of a man 's heart is stonier , Louis .
( GROWLING )
What we did last night ,
we did for Ellie .
But that 's your cat now .
LOUIS : ( MURMURING ) " Bull presumed dead found on main street . "
" Timothy Baterman ... "
" Cadaver disappearance ? "
( TYPING )
What the fuck ?
( SIGHS )
Where did you take me , Jud ?
Church , you 're so stinky .
What 'd you do out there ?
( SNARLING )
Hang on , Church , there 's something ...
Something gross in your fur .
- ( HISSES ) - ( SCREAMS )
( HISSES )
( GROWLING )
LOUIS : All right , there we go .
Give me a look .
Okay . Does that feel okay ?
Yeah ?
I want to go back to our old house .
Well , Mommy and I , we moved up here to slow down ,
so that we could spend more time with you , so that ...
Lift up .
So that Daddy could be around , he 'd get to tuck you into bed more ,
make sure you 're all safe and sound .
- Give you a little tickle before he says good night . - ( GIGGLES )
Okay ? Come on .
Okay , honey . ( KISSES )
I promise , okay , just like your arm , it 's gonna get better .
All right ? Trust me ?
Good night .
- Daddy ? - Yeah ?
Close the door all the way . I don 't want Church coming in anymore .
Okay .
I love you .
RACHEL : How is she ?
She 's good . Poor little thing .
What about Church ?
( SIGHS )
I don 't know . Must 've been the accident .
I 'll take him to the vet tomorrow .
What about you ?
I 'm good .
But ... ( CHUCKLES )
Come here .
( SIGHS )
It 's been hard , the past few months .
( RUSTLING )
( BONE CRACKING )
- ( EXCLAIMS ) - What ? Oh , Jesus !
( SQUAWKS WEAKLY )
Louis , it 's still alive .
( CHURCH GROWLING )
- ( HISSES ) - Damn it !
( HISSES )
Jesus Christ .
( SIGHS )
Church ?
Come out of there , buddy .
( RASPY BREATHING )
- Church ... - ( HISSING VIOLENTLY )
( WATER DRIPPING )
( DRIPPING CONTINUES )
( SOFT , OVERLAPPING WHISPERS )
VICTOR : Your destruction
and the destruction of all you love is very near , Doctor .
( GAGE CRYING IN DISTANCE )
( HORN BLARING )
( GRUNTS )
( PANTING HEAVILY )
( MUFFLED THUMP )
- ( FLOORBOARDS CREAKING ) - ( SOFT THUDDING )
- ( CREAKING CONTINUES ) - ( THUDDING CONTINUES )
( SLIDING )
- ( CREAKING STOPS ) - ( THUDDING STOPS )
- ( CREAKING RESUMES ) - ( THUDDING RESUMES , LOUDER )
( HINGES CREAKING )
- ( CREAKING CONTINUES ) - ( THUDDING CONTINUES )
- ( METAL CLANGS ) - ( MACHINE WHIRRING )
( OBJECTS RATTLING )
( WHIRRING CONTINUES )
- ( METAL CLANGS ) - ( WHIRRING STOPS )
( LOUD SCREECHING )
LOUIS : Rach , what happened ? You okay ?
Mmm .
I don 't want to talk about it .
( SIGHS DEEPLY )
- Is it the bird ? - No , it 's not the bird .
I think it 's a mistake that we moved here .
It doesn 't feel right , Louis .
( SIGHS )
You remember why we moved here in the first place ?
No , I know .
I mean , look , we have Ellie 's birthday coming up .
Why don 't we do something special , hey ?
We could throw a party .
We could invite some of our friends from Boston up , all right ?
Invite your parents , even .
( BOTH CHUCKLE )
- Okay ? - Mmm .
( SIGHS )
We can turn this around . We can .
We can turn this around .
( PENCIL SCRATCHING )
( SIGHS ) Ooh , these are looking good , El .
El , what is this ?
I don 't know . Gage drew that .
( GAGE CRYING )
Gage ?
( GROWLING )
( HISSING )
Come on , Daddy 's got you . Daddy 's got you .
( GAGE CRYING )
JUD : I was 11 when I lost Biff .
He 'd run over some barbed wire and the cuts got infected .
Daddy had to put him down out of mercy .
- Your dad took you up there . - No , no .
It was an old fella named Stanny Bouchard .
He told me about it .
The Wendigo .
You heard a lot about that
all over the north country back in the old days .
It was a myth
passed down from the local tribes up this way .
But to them , it wasn 't just some campfire story .
They believed it . They feared it .
Saw these on the trees up there .
Yeah , they 're warnings .
The local tribes carved them before they fled .
Fled ?
Yeah , they knew the power of that place .
They felt its pull .
( SIGHS ) They came to believe that those woods belonged to something else .
That the ground was bad .
Sour .
The ground is sour .
Yeah .
So , they moved on . But not before they built that deadfall .
( SIGHS )
They built it to keep people out .
But it didn 't keep people out .
( SIGHS ) The Wendigo
may just be some crazy folktale ,
but there is something up there .
Something that brings things back .
So , what happened to your dog , Jud ?
He came back .
Just like Stanny B. said he would . But he was changed .
It was when he went after my mother that my daddy put him down .
For the second time .
I thought it would be different with Ellie 's cat .
I mean , Biff had a mean streak to begin with .
But Church , well ...
- Was a nice cat ... - He tried to hurt Gage .
I 'm so sorry , Louis . I am .
Once you feel the power of that place ,
you make up the sweetest-smelling reasons to go back .
But I was wrong .
Sometimes dead is better .
- ( CHURCH GROWLING ) - Come on , hold still .
Hold still , you 're just gonna go to sleep .
- ( HISSES ) - Damn it , Church . Come on , just ...
( MEOWS )
- ( PURRING ) - God damn it .
Come on .
Hey .
( CLICKING TONGUE )
Good luck .
( PURRING SOFTLY )
( LOW GROWLING )
( ENGINE STARTS )
ALL : ♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday , dear Ellie ♪
( CHILDREN LAUGHING )
( ALL WHOOPING , CLAPPING )
Good job , Ellie .
I want a piece right from the end .
( CHILDREN CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY )
JUD : ... big St. Bernard .
He got rabies . He killed about four people .
( CHATTERING CONTINUES )
Hey .
You still thinking about Church ?
It 's my fault he left .
I told him to get out of my room .
No , honey , no .
Church loves you .
Maybe this might help cheer you up .
Give him a squeeze .
- ( MEOWS ) - Hmm ?
( CHUCKLING )
- I love him , Daddy . - You do ? Yeah ?
And I love you .
Now go and have a great birthday , okay ?
Six ...
ALL : Seven , eight , nine , 10 !
- ( BELLOWING ) - ( CHILDREN SQUEALING , LAUGHING )
LOUIS : I 'm a monster !
Where is everyone ? Where are you guys ? Come on .
( LOUIS BELLOWING )
Come on ! Where is that ... Come on ! Come on !
Church ?
Church !
Church . You came home .
( MEOWS )
LOUIS : All right , you 're it .
Where 's ...
Gage !
( CELL PHONE RINGING )
Church !
( TIRES SCREECHING )
( INAUDIBLE )
( SNIFFLES )
( BREATHING SHAKILY )
I keep thinking
that I 'm gonna hear her coming up the stairs ,
like she 's coming home from school .
I can 't be here right now .
LOUIS : I 'm just gonna wrap up a few things .
RACHEL : Come soon .
- I love you . - LOUIS : I love you , too .
Be a good boy , okay , buddy ? Take care of Mommy for me .
I 'll see you in a couple days .
( ENGINE STARTS )
( GLASSES CLINKING )
I saw Rachel and Gage leaving a little while ago .
Boston .
( BOTTLE UNCORKS )
Parents ' house .
So it 's just you over there ?
Yep .
I 'll drive down in a few days .
I got to finish a few things at the clinic first .
( SIGHS )
That 's good .
It 's a tough time for you folks to be apart .
Yeah .
( PAPER RUSTLING )
You know , when you came walking over here , it was a relief .
I was gonna come to see you .
I should never have shown you that place .
( SOFTLY ) But you did .
I know what you 're thinking of doing , Louis ...
( VOICE BREAKING ) ... but she won 't come back the same .
I 'm so goddamn sorry I did this .
Ellie is the first person to touch my heart in a long time .
I didn 't want her to be so sad .
It 's that goddamn place . It feeds on your grief ,
gets into your mind .
( SIGHS )
( GRUNTS ) Damn it .
( GROANING ) I need to close my eyes for a minute .
( GROANS )
- ( THUNDER RUMBLES ) - ( RAIN PATTERING )
( LINE RINGING )
LOUIS : Hey .
Thought you 'd be in bed .
I was waiting to hear from you . I called earlier .
Yeah , I know , I saw that . I was , uh ...
I went over to Jud 's . Had a couple of drinks .
RACHEL : Can you just come be with us ?
( CLICKS TONGUE )
Gage needs you and I 'm ...
I 'm really wiped out , honey .
Is it okay if we talk tomorrow ?
Okay .
I love you .
I love you , too .
Goodbye .
Fuck .
( OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING )
( SHOVEL THUDS )
( THUNDER RUMBLES )
( FAINT , RASPING BREATH )
( ZELDA WHIMPERING )
( ZELDA GASPING )
( GASPS )
VICTOR : Louis , stop .
I 'm sorry I couldn 't help you .
You have to let her go .
But I can fix this .
GAGE : Pascow !
- Pascow ! Pascow ! - ( DOOR OPENS )
- Come here . No , it 's okay . - ( WHIMPERING )
It 's okay . It 's okay .
VICTOR : Go home .
GAGE : Pascow says go home .
Mommy , go home !
There 's nothing there .
( BREATHING SHAKILY )
( GAGE WHIMPERING )
There 's nothing there .
( DISTANT WAILING )
( BRANCHES SNAPPING , CRASHING )
( CREATURE ROARING IN DISTANCE )
Daddy 's almost there , almost there .
( BRANCHES SNAPPING )
( CREATURE GROWLING )
( GROWLING CONTINUES )
( SOFT , OVERLAPPING WHISPERS )
( INDISTINCT WHISPERS CONTINUE )
( GRUNTS )
( SHRIEKING IN DISTANCE )
- ( BRANCHES SNAPPING ) - ( PANTING )
( WAILING IN DISTANCE )
- ( BRANCHES SNAPPING ) - ( WHISPERING INTENSIFIES )
( HOWLS , WHISPERS INTENSIFY )
( SHOUTING )
( NOISES SUBSIDE )
I 'm sorry .
( SOFT , OVERLAPPING WHISPERS )
( DOOR CREAKS , CLOSES )
( FLOORBOARDS CREAKING )
( LOUIS BREATHING SOFTLY )
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
( WOOD CREAKS )
- ( WOOD CREAKS ) - ( OBJECT THUMPS )
( HINGES CREAKING )
( GASPS )
( SHUDDERING BREATH )
- ( SWITCH CLICKS ) - ( BULB BUZZING )
( FLOORBOARDS CREAKING )
( SNIFFLES )
- Daddy ? - ( GASPS )
Where am I ?
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
Oh , my ... My little girl .
Come here .
Oh , you 're home !
( SNIFFLES )
( LAUGHING WHEEZILY )
( SOBBING )
Home .
( SQUELCHES )
( SIGHS )
What is it ?
Just a tangle .
Where 's Mommy and Gage ?
They went down to Grandma and Grandpa 's .
Are they coming back ?
Yeah .
I remember my birthday party .
Church was out on the road .
I was so happy he came home .
There was a truck .
Then everything went black .
Well , it 's okay now .
Now you 're back .
Back from where ?
It 's time to go to bed , okay ? Turn the light off .
I 'm dead , aren 't I ?
No , honey . No .
You 're here .
Will you stay with me ?
Of course .
I can hear the woods .
( WHISPERING ) The windows are closed , sweetheart .
Not like that .
Inside .
Does Mommy know about me ?
Please , El ...
Close your eyes , okay ?
It 's gonna be okay .
Love you , Daddy .
Love you too , El .
( GRUNTS )
( MUSIC PLAYING )
El ?
( MUSIC PLAYS LOUDER )
( ELLIE GRUNTING )
( GRUNTS )
Ellie , careful .
Just stop it . Stop it . Stop . Ellie , stop it .
- ( GRUNTS ) - Stop it !
Why 'd you put the dress back on ?
( CELL PHONE VIBRATING )
What are you gonna tell her ?
( SIGHS )
( HORNS HONKING )
RACHEL : Something happened last night . I ...
Gage was having a nightmare , or I thought it was a nightmare ,
and he just started saying that boy 's name who died .
I 'm freaking out , and Gage is freaking out ,
and I ... I just need to talk to you .
- Just please call me back . - ( GAGE COOING )
MAN : ( ON RADIO ) It 's 4 : 00 p.m. on the dot
and we 're coming to you with a traffic update .
Expect major delays .
Traffic on the I-95 is backed-up for miles .
- We 're gonna be okay , okay ? - ( RADIO STATIC )
- Okay ? - GAGE : Mama .
- Mama . - PASCOW : ( WHISPERING ) Call Jud .
So far , no fatalities , but two passengers have been airlifted ...
- JUD : ( OVER PHONE ) Yeah ? - Jud , hi , it 's Rachel .
( STUTTERING ) Rachel . You ...
You down at your folks ' place ?
Yeah , I 'm on my way back . Something 's wrong .
I 'm really worried about Louis right now .
- Louis ? - Can you just go over there
and check on him , please ?
I just ... I 've been calling him all morning , and I don 't know ...
( STUTTERING ) What ... He ... He 's not answering ?
No . And I 've called him so many times .
- Well , I 'll go on over there and check . - Okay . Thank you , Jud .
I should be there soon , okay ?
Yeah , I 'll see you then , Rachel .
( LINE DISCONNECTS )
( PHONE BEEPS )
Louis ? You in there ?
Hey , Jud .
How 's your head today ?
Oh . ( CHUCKLES )
( LAUGHING ) It 's banging like a drum , Jud .
I don 't remember you leaving last night .
Yeah , you passed out .
Listen , I got to , uh ...
I got to get back inside . I 'm ...
I 've been waiting for Rachel to call all morning
and I don 't want to miss it . So ...
Okay ?
If you 've done something , Louis ,
it 's not too late to undo it .
You don 't have to worry about me , Jud .
I 'm fine .
Really .
If that 's all , I 'm gonna ...
I 'm gonna go .
( PANTING )
( THUD )
( FLOORBOARD CREAKING )
( PANTING )
I know you 're up here !
( DOOR CREAKS )
( GLASS SHATTERS )
( FLOORBOARD CREAKING )
( GRUNTS )
( PANTING )
( EXHALES SHARPLY )
( CHURCH GROWLING )
( PURRING )
( LAUGHS )
( ELLIE YELLS )
( GROANING )
( GASPING AND GROANING )
- Hello , Jud . - Stop it , Ellie .
Now , just slow down .
Your sweet Norma .
She 's burning down in hell for what you did to her .
I saw her there , Jud . I saw her .
Shut up ! You don 't know anything about her !
( GROWLS )
Did you miss me , Judson ?
That 's not my Norma !
( SCREAMING )
Ellie 's hurting . You did this to her !
It 's not you . It 's not you !
You told Louis about that place .
And now we 're suffering
( WHISPERING ) eternally .
But we 're here now to bring you back
so you can suffer with us .
Just you come and fucking try !
( JUD SCREAMING )
( PURRING )
LOUIS : El ?
- ( CAR DOOR SHUTS ) - ( CAR ALARM BEEPS )
Oh , shit .
Rachel .
What are you ... ( CHUCKLES )
You 're okay . Thank God you 're okay !
I was so worried , and I was calling
and you wouldn 't pick up , and
Gage was having these nightmares
and he was saying the name of that boy that died .
I 'm here right now . I just need you and no one else .
Just you , me and Gage ,
- we can get through this . - It 's okay . It 's okay .
Come on , honey , it 's okay .
- Oh . Oh . - ( GASPS )
- Look at you , hey ? You 're Daddy 's boy . - Daddy .
Have you gotten bigger ? Hey ? Tell me , come on .
Have you gotten bigger ? I think he has . I think he has .
I think he 's gotten a lot bigger .
Oh , you smell so good ! Hmm .
Oh , you smell so good ! Come to Daddy .
( BREATH TREMBLING ) Louis , what 's going on ?
I needed more time with her .
Come here . Come here .
Honey .
I wasn 't ready to say goodbye to her .
You 're scaring me .
Just tell me what you 're talking about .
It was my fault she died , Rach .
I had to bring her back .
Ellie-phant .
( BREATH TREMBLING )
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
( GASPING )
The Great and Terrible .
There 's a place , Rach , deep in the woods
beyond the pet cemetery .
( GASPING AND SOBBING )
It brings things back .
Aren 't you happy , Mommy ?
( SOBBING )
( RACHEL GASPS )
( WHISPERING ) Hug your daughter , Rach .
Hug your daughter .
(
HYPERVENTILATING ) I need to put Gage to bed .
- ( GAGE MUMBLING ) - LOUIS : Rachel !
She doesn 't want me here .
( GAGE CRYING )
No , no , no , no , no . Mommy just needs time .
It 's okay . I don 't want her here , either .
We 're okay . Okay , yes .
Here you go . Here you go , sweetie .
- ( KNOCKING AT DOOR ) - LOUIS : Rachel .
Rachel , open up . Please .
Just let me explain .
I know . Let me explain .
( STUTTERING ) What is she ? What is ...
That is Ellie out there .
No . No , we buried her . We put her in the ground .
She 's been given back to us . We have a second chance .
It doesn 't work that way , Louis .
Yes , it does . There 's a place in the woods .
That place I was telling you about .
I couldn 't understand it until I buried Church up there .
That cat was dead until I buried him in the ground
and it brought him back .
He wasn 't the same after that .
You saw her .
You touched her . That is our daughter .
( SOBBING ) You dug her up ?
That is our daughter down there , honey .
Please , okay ?
I did what I think was right .
Let God take his own fucking kid !
( FLOORBOARD CREAKING )
( GASPING )
- LOUIS : Ellie ? - RACHEL : You 're okay .
Ellie !
Ellie , baby , Mommy and Daddy were just ...
Shit .
Mama .
It 's okay , sweetie . It 's okay .
Mommy 's okay . Mommy 's ...
- ( THUD ) - ( GASPS )
- ( WHIMPERING ) - ( SCREECHING )
( FOOTSTEPS OVERHEAD )
No . No , no , no . No , no , no ...
No .
( GASPS )
( BREATH TREMBLING )
( GASPING )
( GASPING AND SOBBING )
( THUDS AND CREAKING )
( INDISTINCT MOANING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( BONES CRACKING )
( RACHEL GROANING )
Rachel .
( RACHEL SCREAMS )
NORMA : Now you 'll never get out of bed again .
( GASPING )
( RACHEL SCREAMS )
No ! No !
Stop struggling , you useless cow .
( RACHEL GRUNTING )
Ellie ?
Shit .
( GAGE CRYING )
( RACHEL SCREAMING )
( RACHEL GROANS )
( GRUNTING )
Jud !
( CHURCH PURRING )
Oh , my God .
Oh , my God . No , Jud .
( SNIFFLES )
God damn it !
( GROANING )
( BANGING ON DOOR CONTINUES )
( ELLIE GRUNTS )
( SOBBING )
( ELLIE SCREAMS )
( BANGING ON DOOR CONTINUES )
RACHEL : Louis ! Take the baby !
- Louis ! - Rachel !
Take the baby ! Ellie 's trying to kill me !
- Come on , I got him . Jump ! - Take the baby !
Let him go ! Come on , Daddy 's got you .
Come on .
( GROANS )
( GASPS AND THUDS )
( LAUGHS )
Okay . Okay , Gage .
Daddy needs you to stay in the car , okay ?
Don 't open the door for anyone .
Listen to me , Gage , not even for Ellie .
( LABORED BREATHING )
You let me die in that road . You did nothing .
Just like you did with your sister .
I was scared .
( GROANING )
You 're a liar .
You prayed your sister would die .
I did .
Remember when Daddy said there was nothing after this ?
Well , he was wrong .
But it 's not heaven .
And you 're going there soon , Mommy .
Don 't call me " Mommy . "
You 're not my daughter .
Ellie 's dead .
Then go be with her !
( SCREAMS )
Rachel !
Oh , God , Rach . I got Gage .
Don 't bury me in that place .
What ?
( GROANS )
( GROANING )
Oh , fuck . Shit .
( SIGHS )
Rachel !
ELLIE : You 're too late .
Where 's Mommy ?
ELLIE : Mommy 's already feasting on dirt .
What have you done , El ? Come on .
You started this , Daddy .
When you moved us here .
When you buried Church .
When you buried me ! ( SCREAMS )
( LOUIS AND ELLIE SCREAMING )
( BOTH GRUNTING )
Stop fighting , Daddy .
It will be better this way .
( ELLIE SCREAMS )
( LOUIS GROANING )
LOUIS : You 're dead ! You 're dead !
( GRUNTING AND SCREAMING )
( ELLIE GRUNTING )
You 're dead !
LOUIS : Please , please , just stop .
Get off !
I thought we could be a family .
I wanted to be a family .
But we can 't .
But we can , Daddy . We can .
( SCREAMS )
( FIRE CRACKLING )
( CAR ALARM BEEPS )
Subtitles by explosiveskull Sync by GoldenBeard